<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Lingoose - Tag - Simone Vellei - Blog</title><link>https://simonevellei.com/tags/lingoose/</link><description>Lingoose - Tag - Simone Vellei - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>it</language><managingEditor>henomis@gmail.com (Simone Vellei)</managingEditor><webMaster>henomis@gmail.com (Simone Vellei)</webMaster><copyright>© 2025 Simone Vellei. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:51:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simonevellei.com/tags/lingoose/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anthropic's Claude Integration with Go and Lingoose</title><link>https://simonevellei.com/anthropic-claude-integration-with-go-and-lingoose/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:51:58 +0100</pubDate><author>Simone Vellei</author><guid>https://simonevellei.com/anthropic-claude-integration-with-go-and-lingoose/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/lingoose003.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>In the ever-changing world of artificial intelligence, a new AI assistant called <a href="https://claude.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Claude</a> has arrived on the scene, and it&rsquo;s turning heads. Created by a company called <a href="https://anthropic.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Anthropic</a>, Claude is incredibly smart and can understand and communicate with humans in very natural, human-like ways.</p>
<p>What makes Claude so special is the way it has been trained. The folks at Anthropic fed Claude a massive amount of data, which allows it to truly grasp how we humans speak and write. So whether you&rsquo;re chatting with Claude casually or asking it to tackle some complex task, it can handle it all with impressive skill.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Empowering Go: unveiling the synergy of AI and Q&amp;A pipelines</title><link>https://simonevellei.com/empowering-go-unveiling-the-synergy-of-ai-and-qa-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:24:42 +0100</pubDate><author>Simone Vellei</author><guid>https://simonevellei.com/empowering-go-unveiling-the-synergy-of-ai-and-qa-pipelines/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/lingoose002.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>In the realm of artificial intelligence and machine learning, efficient similarity search is a critical component for tasks ranging from recommendation systems to image recognition. In this blog post, we&rsquo;ll explore the implementation of vector similarity search in Go, utilizing <a href="https://github.com/henomis/lingoose" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">LinGoose</a> framework for indexing and querying vectors in a <a href="https://qdrant.tech/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Qdrant</a> database.</p>
<h2 id="understanding-vector-similarity-search">Understanding Vector Similarity Search</h2>
<p>Vector similarity search involves finding vectors in a dataset that are most similar to a query vector. This is fundamental in various AI applications where matching or ranking similar items is required. Qdrant, a vector database, provides a robust solution for such searches.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Leveraging Go and Redis for Efficient Retrieval Augmented Generation</title><link>https://simonevellei.com/leveraging-go-and-redis-for-efficient-retrieval-augmented-generation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 17:06:47 +0100</pubDate><author>Simone Vellei</author><guid>https://simonevellei.com/leveraging-go-and-redis-for-efficient-retrieval-augmented-generation/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/lingoose001.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Artificial Intelligence has transformed the way we handle data, and one crucial aspect of AI is similarity search. Whether it&rsquo;s for image recognition, recommendation systems, or natural language processing, finding similar data points quickly and accurately is a common challenge. In this blog post, we will explore a Go code snippet that showcases how to perform efficient vector similarity search using Redis and the <a href="https://github.com/henomis/lingoose" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Lingoose</a> Go framework, catering to tech-savvy readers interested in both Go programming and AI.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>